(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-06T04:48:40.325521",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
so, everything that makes me whole
今君に捧げよう
I'll dedicate to you right now.
I'm Yours
ねえ こんなに笑えたこと
Hey, being able to smile like this—
生まれて初めてだよ
it's the first time in my life.
きっと 私はね
Surely, I...
この日の為に 間違いだらけの
For the sake of this day, on a path full of mistakes...
道を歩いてきたんだ
I've walked all this way.
ずっと 一人で
Always all alone...
遠く 遠く どこまでも遠く
Far, far away, no matter how far...
君と二人 手を取って 永遠に
The two of us, holding hands forever.
どこまでだって 行けるはず
We should be able to go anywhere.
もう一人じゃないと
Knowing I'm no longer alone...
君は遠い
You are far away,
また笑う
and yet you smile again.
守るべき大事なものが今あって
There's something precious I must protect right now,
だけど進む術もなく立ち尽くす時は
but when I have no way forward and stand paralyzed,
可能性を失って
losing all possibilities,
闇が君を覆い隠して
as darkness envelops you,
絶望に飲み込まれそうな時は
when you're about to be swallowed by despair,
私が君を照らす明かりになるから
I will become the light that shines upon you,
たとえこの世界の王にだって消せはしない
even the king of this world cannot extinguish it.
so, everything that makes me whole 今君に捧げよう
so, everything that makes me whole, I dedicate to you now.
I'm Yours
ねえ この世界にはたくさんの幸せがあるんだね
You know, there is so much happiness in this world, isn't there?
いつか二人なら
if someday, we are together as two.
誰かが君のことを嘘つきと呼んで
Even if someone calls you a liar,
心無い言葉で傷つけようとしても
and tries to hurt you with heartless words,
世界が君のことを信じようともせずに
even if the world refuses to believe in you,
茨の冠を被せようとしても
and tries to crown you with thorns,
私は君だけの味方になれるよ
I can become your only ally.
その孤独 痛みを私は知っている
I know that loneliness and pain.
so, everything that makes me whole 今君に捧げよう
so, everything that makes me whole, I dedicate to you now.
I'm Yours
いつか私を知ることができたなら
If you could come to know me someday,
必ずその場所に私はいるから
I will surely be in that place.
そこに希望の欠片すらなかったとしても
Even if there isn't a single fragment of hope there,
私が在ってはならないものであっても
even if I am something that should not exist,
君は忘れないでいてくれることを
the fact that you will remember me—
誰よりも私がそのことを知っている
I know that better than anyone else.
だから私は君のために全てを今捧げよう
So for your sake, I will dedicate everything to you now.
今捧げよう
I dedicate it now.
I'm Yours
鉄の弾が正義の証明
An iron bullet is the proof of justice;
貫けば英雄に近づいた
piercing through it brings you closer to a hero.
その目を閉じて触れてみれば 同じ形 同じ体温の悪魔
If you close your eyes and touch, you'll find a demon of the same shape and warmth.
僕はダメで あいつはいいの?
Why is it bad for me, but okay for him?
そこに壁があっただけなのに
Even though there was just a wall between us,
生まれてしまった運命嘆くな 僕らはみんな自由なんだから
don't lament the fate of being born, because we are all free.
鳥のように羽があれば どこへだって行けるけど
If we had wings like birds, we could go anywhere,
帰る場所がなければ きっとどこへも行けない
but without a place to return to, surely we can go nowhere.
ただただ生きるのは嫌だ
I hate just merely living.
世界は残酷だ それでも君を愛するよ
This world is cruel, but even so, I will love you.
鉄の弾が 正義の証明
An iron bullet is proof of justice,
貫けば 英雄に近づいた
shooting through brings one closer to a hero.
その目を閉じて 触れてみれば
If you close your eyes and touch it,
同じ形 同じ体温の悪魔
you'll find a devil with the same shape and warmth.
僕はダメで あいつはいいの?
Why am I wrong while they are fine?
そこに壁があっただけなのに
Even though there was just a wall between us.
生まれてきてしまった 運命嘆くな
Don't lament the fate of being born,
僕らはみんな 自由なんだから
because we are all free.
鉄の雨が 降り散る情景
A scene of iron rain falling scattered,
テレビの中 映画に見えたんだ
seen on TV like a movie.
戦争なんて 愚かな兇暴
War is such foolish brutality,
関係ない 知らない国の話
a story of an unrelated, unknown country.
それならなんで あいつを憎んで
Then why do I hate them so much,
黒い気持ち 隠しきれない理由
and why can't I hide these dark feelings?
説明だって できやしないんだ
I can't even explain it at all.
僕らはなんて 矛盾ばっかなんだ
We are just full of contradictions.
この言葉も 訳されれば
Even if these words are translated,
本当の意味は 伝わらない
their true meaning won't be conveyed.
信じるのは その目を開いて
What to believe in... open your eyes
触れた世界だけ
to the world you've touched.
ただただ生きるのは嫌だ
I hate the thought of just merely living.
世界は残酷だ
The world is cruel,
それでも君を愛するよ
but even so, I will love you.
なにを犠牲にしても
No matter what I sacrifice,
それでも君を守るよ
I will still protect you.
間違いだとしても
Even if it's a mistake,
疑ったりしない
I won't doubt it at all.
正しさは 自分のこと 強く信じることだ
Righteousness is strongly believing in yourself.
選んだ人の影 捨てたものの屍
Shadows of chosen people, corpses of discarded things—
気づいたんだ 自分の中 育つのは悪魔の子
I realized that what grows inside me is an evil child.
正義の裏 犠牲の中 心には悪魔の子
Behind righteousness, amidst sacrifice, in my heart is an evil child.
Hi everyone! It's IRyS from Hololive English Promise,
Hololive English's IRyS desu! Welcome
to my 3rd anniversary live, The Devil Wears Hope!
Woo! I know it's a little late due to scheduling issues,
but I'm so glad I'm finally able to do this! Yeah!
Etto... Welcome to IRyS no, etto, The Devil Wears Hope, etto, 3 shuunen no live e youkoso!
Um... Welcome to IRyS's—um, The Devil Wears Hope—um, welcome to the 3rd anniversary live!
Thank you very much for coming, kite kudasari arigatou gozaimasu!
Thank you very much for coming!
How'd you guys like the first two songs?
Yes, my dears, Nakaman-tachi! Did you guys notice that
Yes, my dears, Nakama-tachi! Did you guys notice that
they are held on different stages? Akuma no koto... my dears, doudeshita ka?
they were held on different stages? How was it, my dears?
Yeah? This where I'm right now is the Devil stage, is very pretty and purple.
Yeah? Where I am right now is the Devil stage, very pretty and purple.
And over there is where the beautiful angelic stage is. Yes! I will be moving around quite a lot this live to sing many songs.
And over there is where the beautiful angelic stage is. Yes! I'll be moving around quite a lot this live to sing many songs.
And even though there's two stages, there might be even more! Nanto ne, kono, ano, double stage de ohirou sasete itadakimasu...
And even though there are two stages, there might be even more!
As you guys can tell by now, this theme, uh, the theme of this live this time is angel and devil theme...
As you guys can tell by now, the theme of this live is an angel and devil theme!
Etto, konkai no ne, live no tema wa nanto, tenshi to akuma desu!
Um, the theme of this live is none other than angels and devils!
I will be singing a lot of songs with a lot of guests, and there might be a very special announcement!
I'll be singing a lot of songs with many guests, and there might be a very special announcement!
So I hope you guys look forward to that, yeah? Make sure you watch till the end!
So I hope you guys look forward to that! Make sure you watch till the end!
ねえ、つづいて、おねがいしまーす！
Next up, please!
えーっとね、このあとたくさんの曲を、たくさんのステージでね、
Um, after this, we'll sing lots of songs, on lots of stages,
そう、たくさんのゲストを最後まで歌えますんで、
yes, with lots of guests, until the very end,
みんな最後まで見てね！
so everyone watch until the end!
あとね、それどころかもうね、あの、とっても素敵な告知も最後の方にあるんで、最後まで見てください！
And what's more, there's even a very wonderful announcement towards the end, so please watch until the end!
では、Please... I have to go to the next stage
Well then, please... I have to go to the next stage
again to sing more songs. Then right back! Yeah!
again to sing more songs. I'll be right back, yeah!
Next up to the next song!
Let's go to the next song!
あと一度だけ 奇跡は起きるだろう
One more time, a miracle will happen,
優しい声で描く 歪んだ未来
painting a twisted future with a gentle voice.
もう誰も泣かない 世界の為に
For the sake of a world where no one cries anymore,
紅く汚された空の
in the red-stained sky,
何処にも届かず消える叫びと祈り
screams and prayers fade away, reaching nowhere.
慰めは捨てて行ける 綺麗な月明かりが
Leaving comfort behind, the beautiful moonlight
始まりへと沈み行く その彼方に
sinks into the beginning, beyond that horizon.
閉ざされてく瞳で まだ遠くへ 手を伸ばす
With closing eyes, still reaching out far away—
君の嘆きを信じて
believing in your lament.
本当は誰が 救われたくて
Who really wanted to be saved?
迷う心が 空に穴を穿つ
A wandering heart bores a hole in the sky.
君を選んで たった二人の喜びを探せたなら
If I chose you and sought the joy of just the two of us,
どんな冷たい焔に 身を焼かれても
no matter how cold the flames burn my body,
微笑みの近く のたうつ夢の命の意味
close to your smile, the writhing meaning of life in dreams.
怖がれているこの世界を 澄んだ水の中へ還したい
I want to return this frightened world back into the clear waters.
悲しみだけ消せはしない そんな人の心さえ
Just erasing sadness won't do; even the heart of man...
この手で切り裂いて
I'll tear apart with these hands.
down to zero we go
綺麗な月明かりは
The beautiful moonlight
ただ静かに
quietly
始まりへ朽ちて行くよ
decays into the beginning.
閉ざされた憧れは
The closed-off longing
まだ遠くへ
is still far away,
闇の中
in the dark.
どんな冷たい焔に 身を焼かれても
No matter how cold the flames burn my body,
微笑みの近く のたうつ夢の命の意味
close to your smile, the writhing meaning of life in dreams.
怖がれているこの世界を 澄んだ水の中へ還したい
I want to return this frightened world back into the clear waters.
悲しみだけ消せはしない そんな人の心さえ
Just erasing sadness won't do; even the heart of man...
この手で切り裂いて
I'll tear apart with these hands.
down to zero we go
綺麗な月明かりは ただ静かに
The beautiful moonlight quietly
始まりへ朽ちて行くよ
decays into the beginning.
閉ざされた憧れは まだ遠くへ
The closed-off longing is still far away,
闇の中 君と生きた日々の全て
in the dark, all the days I lived with you...
優しい歌
a gentle song.
あと一度だけ 奇跡は起きるだろう
One more time, a miracle will happen,
優しい声で描く 歪んだ未来
painting a twisted future with a gentle voice.
もう誰も泣かない 世界の為に
for the sake of a world where no one cries anymore.
紅く汚された空の 何処にも届かず消える叫びと祈り
In the red-stained sky, screams and prayers fade away, reaching nowhere.
慰めは捨てて行ける
Leaving comfort behind,
綺麗な月明かりが
the beautiful moonlight
始まりへと沈み行く その彼方に
sinks into the beginning, beyond that horizon.
目覚めては繰り返す
Waking up and repeating,
眠い朝は
sleepy mornings,
襟のタイをきつく締め
tightening my collar tie,
教室のドアくぐると
passing through the classroom door,
ほんの少し
just a little,
胸を張って歩き出せる
I can walk out with my head held high.
そんな日常に吹き抜ける風
A wind blowing through such everyday life,
聞こえた気がした
I felt like I heard it,
感じた気がしたんだ
I felt like I felt it.
震え出す今この胸で
In this heart now trembling,
もう来る気がした
I felt like it's already coming.
幾億の星が消え去ってくのを
Watching countless stars fade and vanish away,
見送った 手を振った
I saw them off, I waved goodbye.
よかったねと
Saying, "I'm glad,"
廊下の隅見下ろす
Looking down from the corner of the hallway,
掃除の途中
midway through cleaning,
おかしなものだと思う
I think it's such a strange thing.
あたしの中の時は止まってるのに
Even though time inside me has stopped,
違う日々を生きてるように
As if living in different days,
埃は雪のように降り積む
Dust piles up like falling snow.
待ってる気がした
I thought it was waiting,
呼んでる気がしたんだ
I thought it was calling out.
震え出す今この時が
In this very moment now trembling,
見つけた気がした
I felt like I found it.
失われた記憶が呼び覚ました
Lost memories were awakened.
物語 永遠の その終わり
A story... the end of eternity.
いつの間にか駆けだしてた
Before I knew it, I was running,
あなたに手を引かれてた
Being led by the hand by you.
昨日は遠く 明日はすぐ
Yesterday is far, tomorrow is near,
そんな当たり前に心が躍った
My heart danced at such a natural thing.
聞こえた気がした
I felt like I heard it,
感じた気がしたんだ
I felt like I felt it.
震え出す今この胸で
In this heart now trembling,
もう来る気がした
I felt like it's already coming.
幾千の朝を越え 新しい陽が
Crossing thousands of mornings, a new sun...
待ってる気がした
I thought it was waiting,
呼んでる気がしたんだ
I thought it was calling out.
震えてるこの魂が
This soul now trembling,
見つけた気がした
I felt like I found it.
幾億の夢のように消え去れる日を見送った 手を振った
Watching the day vanish like billions of dreams, I saw it off, I waved goodbye.
ありがとうと
Saying, "Thank you."
ラストチャンスに飢えたつま先が 踊り出すまま駆け出したこの夜空
My toes, hungry for a last chance, danced as I ran through this night sky.
並みのスタンスじゃ軽やかじゃない
An ordinary stance won't make it light,
星は宝石の憧れ
Stars are the longing of jewels.
浮かす涙と汗は血の名残
Floating tears and sweat are traces of blood.
ラストチャンスに飢えたつま先が
The tips of my toes, starving for a last chance,
踊り出すまま駆けたこの夜空
jump for joy into this starry night sky I run through.
波のスタンスじゃ響かない
With the stance of the waves, there is no response,
星は宝石の憧れ
the stars are the aspiration for gemstones.
浮かぶ涙と汗は血の名残り
Floating tears and sweat are remnants of blood,
目の中でしか泳ぎなきゃ芝居
I can only swim within my own eyes,
だけどステージが逃がさない
but the stage won't let me escape.
いついつまでも
Forever and ever,
憧れ焦がれているよ
I am yearning and burning for it.
I've never seen such a liar.
生まれつきだっての底なし
Born into this bottomless void,
This lie is love. And this lie is a gift to the world.
誰と生きたか思い出して
Remember who you lived with,
わたしが命を削るから あげるから
because I am shaving my life and giving it to you,
あなたは時間をくれたのでしょう?
you gave me your time, didn't you?
あらゆる望みの全てを叶えたら ああ果てせたら
If I fulfill all my desires, ah, if I reach the end,
あなたに会いたい 星に願いをかけて
I want to see you, making a wish upon the stars.
戻れないから大切にするの?
Do you cherish it because you can't go back?
始めないなら高を括れるよ
If you don't start, you can afford to be smug.
楽になる日はまず来ない
The day you find relief will never come,
日々の中に集まる悲しい光
sad light gathers within our days.
生まれつきだってば底なし
Born into this bottomless void,
This lie is love. And this lie is a gift to the world.
誰を生きたか忘れちゃった!
I forgot who I lived for!
あなたに命が戻るなら 届くなら
If life returns to you, if it reaches you,
わたしはどうなろうと構わないのに
even though I don't care what happens to me,
どうやらすべては叶わない 叶わないならば
somehow none of it comes true. If it doesn't come true,
あなたになりたい 星は砕け光る
I want to become you. The stars shatter and shine.
わたしが命を削るから あげるから
Because I am shaving my life and giving it,
あなたは時間をくれたのでしょう?
you gave me your time, didn't you?
あらゆる望みの全てを叶えたら ああ果てせたら
If I fulfill all my desires, ah, if I reach the end,
あなたに会いたい 星に願いをかけて
I want to see you, making a wish upon the stars.
さあ星の子たちよ よくお眠りなさい
Now, children of the stars, sleep soundly.
輝きは眠らない あなたたちならば
If you are the ones whose radiance never sleeps,
さあ星の子たちよ よく狙いなさい
now, children of the stars, aim well.
またたきを許さない あなたたちならば
If you are the ones who allow no blinking,
ぴぴるぴぴるぴぴるぴぴるぴ〜
Pi piru piru piru pi piru pi~
何でもできちゃうバット エスカリボルグ！
The bat that can do anything: Excaliborg!
ぴぴるぴぴるぴぴるぴぴるぴ〜
Pi piru piru piru pi piru pi~
魔法の擬音で人生やり直してあげる
I'll redo your life with magical onomatopoeia!
いやよだめよこんなの
No way, stop it, not this!
そんなにギラギラしないで お願いだから えいっ！
Don't glare at me so much, please! Take this!
撲殺天使 血しぶき ドクドク ドクロちゃん
Club-to-death angel, blood splashing, Dokuro-chan!
撲殺天使 心臓 ドクドク ドクロちゃん
Club-to-death angel, heart beating, Dokuro-chan!
撃って燃やして甚振って埋めて塞ぎで侮辱して
Shoot, burn, abuse, bury, block, and insult you,
でも それってボクの「愛」なの
but that's just my "love"!
ぴぴるぴぴるぴぴるぴぴるぴ〜
Pi piru piru piru pi piru pi~
万能 血まみれ バット エスカリボルグ！
The almighty, blood-stained bat: Excaliborg!
ぴぴるぴぴるぴぴるぴぴるぴ〜
Pi piru piru piru pi piru pi~
不思議な擬音で夢かなえてあげる
I'll make your dreams come true with mystic onomatopoeia!
いやーん ばかーん うっふん ダメダメ
No way, silly, ah, absolutely not!
そんなにムラムラしないで お願いだから えいっ！
Don't get so riled up, please! Take this!
撲殺天使 バットで ドス ドス ドクロちゃん
Club-to-death angel, thudding with a bat, Dokuro-chan!
撲殺天使 血みどろどろどろ ドクロちゃん
Club-to-death angel, drenched in blood, Dokuro-chan!
ぴぴるぴるぴるぴぴるぴ 〜
Pi-piru-piru-piru-pi-piru-pi~
何でもできちゃうバット エスカリボルグ！
The bat that can do anything: Excaliborg!
ぴぴるぴるぴるぴぴるぴ 〜
Pi-piru-piru-piru-pi-piru-pi~
魔法の擬音で人生やり直してあげる
With this magic spell, I'll redo your life!
いやよだめよこんなのバカバカ
No way, don't be so idiotic!
そんなにギラギラしないでお願いだからえいっ！
Don't glare at me like that, please! Yeah!
撲殺天使 血しぶき ドクロちゃん
Bludgeoning angel, blood-splattered, Dokuro-chan!
撲殺天使 心臓 ドクロちゃん
Bludgeoning angel, bleeding heart, Dokuro-chan!
踏んで縛って叩いて けってじらしで吊るしてて
I'll step on, tie up, and beat you!
でもそれってボクの「愛」なの
But that's just my way of expressing love!
ぴぴるぴるぴるぴぴるぴ 〜
Pi-piru-piru-piru-pi-piru-pi~
天才とげとげバット エスカリボルグ
The genius, thorny bat: Excaliborg!
ぴぴるぴるぴるぴぴるぴ 〜
Pi-piru-piru-piru-pi-piru-pi~
かわいい擬音で人生ドキドキバクバク
With this cute spell, your life gets thrilling!
は ふん あ ひ ぃ ぱ ぷ ぅ 許して
Ah, phew, ah, hee, hi, puff, forgive me!
そんなにギトギトしないでお願いだからえいっ！
Don't look at me so intensely, please! Yeah!
撲殺天使 血まつり どんどこ ドクロちゃん
Bludgeoning angel, bloodbath, Dokuro-chan!
撲殺天使 鼻血 どぴゅどぴゅ ドクロちゃん
Bludgeoning angel, nosebleed, Dokuro-chan!
抱いて抱かれて閉じ込めて 泣いて笑って殺してて
I'll hold, be held by, and shut you in!
でもそれってボクの「愛」なの
But that's just my way of expressing love!
撲殺天使 バットでドスドス ドクロちゃん
Bludgeoning angel with a bat, Dokuro-chan!
撲殺天使 血みどろどろどろ ドクロちゃん
Bludgeoning angel, blood-soaked, Dokuro-chan!
切って殴って殴って 刺してさらして垂らしてて
I'll cut, punch, punch, pierce, and drop!
でもそれってボクの「愛」なの
But that's just my way of expressing love!
ぴぴるぴるぴるぴぴるぴ 〜
Pi-piru-piru-piru-pi-piru-pi~
何でもできちゃうバット エスカリボルグ！
The bat that can do anything: Excaliborg!
ぴぴるぴるぴるぴぴるぴ 〜
Pi-piru-piru-piru-pi-piru-pi~
魔法の擬音で人生やり直してあげる
With this magic spell, I'll redo your life!
いやよだめよこんなのバカバカ
No way, don't be so idiotic!
そんなにギラギラしないでお願いだからえいっ！
Don't glare at me like that, please! Yeah!
撲殺天使 血しぶき ドクロちゃん
Bludgeoning angel, blood-splattered, Dokuro-chan!
撲殺天使 心臓 ドクロちゃん
Bludgeoning angel, bleeding heart, Dokuro-chan!
踏んで縛って叩いて けってじらしで吊るしてて
I'll step on, tie up, and beat you!
でもそれってボクの「愛」なの
But that's just my way of expressing love!
ぴぴるぴるぴるぴぴるぴ 〜
Pi-piru-piru-piru-pi-piru-pi~
この世で造花より綺麗な花は無いわ
There are no flowers in this world more beautiful than fake ones.
何故ならば全ては嘘で出来ている
Why? Because they're all made of lies.
antipathy world
絶望の雨はあたしの傘を突いて
The rain of despair pierces my umbrella.
湿らす前髪とこころの裏面
Damp bangs and the back of my heart.
絶望の雨はあたしの傘を突いて
The rain of despair pierces my umbrella,
湿らす前髪とこころの裏面
dampening my bangs and the back of my heart.
煩わしいわ
How annoying.
何時しか言葉の葉は疾うに枯れきって
Someday, the leaves of words withered in vexation,
事の真実があたしに売れている
and the truth of the matter is selling to me.
鏡に映り嘘を描いて
Drawing false reflections in the mirror,
自らを見失った絵画
a painting where I lost sight of myself.
パッパラパッパラパッパララッパッパ
Pappa-para-pappala-ra-pappa,
謎々数えて遊びましょう
let's count and play with riddles.
タッタタラタッタラタッタラタッタ
Tatta-tara-tattara-ra-tatta,
何故何故此処で踊っているのでしょう
why, why are we dancing here?
簡単なことも解らないわ あたしって何だっけ
I don't even understand simple things, what am I again?
それすら夜の手に取り残されて
Even that is caught in the hands of the night,
愛のように消える
fading away like love.
さようならも言えぬまま泣いた
I couldn't even say goodbye and softly cried.
フォニー フォニー フォニー
Phony, phony, phony,
嘘に絡まっている
I am entangled in lies.
あたしはフォニー
I am a phony.
antipathy world
何時しか空の音がいやに鳴り合って
When did the sounds of the sky start ringing annoyingly?
色の目があなたを溶いている
Colored eyes are melting you away.
鏡に映るあたしを欠いて
Losing the me reflected in the mirror,
誰もが見間違った虚像
a false image that everyone misunderstood.
何して愛なんてものに群がり
How do I swarm to things like love,
それを欲して生きるのだ
and live desiring it?
今日も泳いでいる夜の電車が
Today too, the night train I'm swimming in
通り去っていく 踊り明かせよ
is passing by, let's dance the night away!
パッパラパッパラパッパララッパッパ
Pappa-para-pappala-ra-pappa,
謎々騙して歌いましょう
let's trick and sing with riddles.
タッタタラタッタラタッタラタッタ
Tatta-tara-tattara-ra-tatta,
何故何故此処が痛むのでしょう
why, why does it hurt here?
惨々な日々は変わらないわ
These miserable days never change.
絶望の雨はやまないわ
The rain of despair will not stop.
さようならも言えぬまま泣いた
I couldn't even say goodbye and cried.
フォニー フォニー フォニー
Phony, phony, phony,
嘘に絡まっている
I am entangled in lies.
嘘に絡まっている ただ
Trapped in lies, just...
簡単なことも分からないわ あたしって何だっけ
I don't even understand the simplest things. Who am I again?
それすら夜の手にほどかれて
Even that is undone by the hands of the night,
愛のように消える 消える
disappearing like love.
さようならまたねと呟いた フォニイ
I murmured 'goodbye, see you later,' Phony.
嘘に絡まっている あたしはフォニイ
Trapped in lies, I am a phony.
造花だけが知っている 秘密のフォニイ
Only the artificial flowers know this secret phony.
微睡みの淵で目蓋に揺蕩う 夢想の神は優雅に微笑み死を降す
Drifting at the edge of slumber beneath the eyelids, the god of dreams smiles gracefully and brings death.
時空を総べる因果の鎖は絡み出す 神の与えし空想 Program
The chains of causality governing space-time begin to entangle. The fantasy program bestowed by the gods.
さあ eins zwei drei! 重なり合う さあ eins zwei drei! 死を避けて 滅滅の遊戯に焦がれる奇跡を奪う Survivalgame 螺旋のように
Now, eins zwei drei! Overlapping. Now, eins zwei drei! Avoiding death. Stealing the miracle yearned for in the game of destruction, Survivalgame, like a spiral.
泡の未来図書き換えるように 空想繋ぐ輪廻のノイズが鳴り渡る 時間は歪み因果の旋律は崩れ去る 神の与えし継承 Program
As if rewriting the future map of bubbles, the noise of reincarnation connecting fantasies resounds. Time distorts and the melody of causality crumbles. The succession program bestowed by the gods.
さあ eins zwei drei! 連なり合う さあ eins zwei drei! 死を振り切って 滅滅の遊戯に抗う奇跡に挑む Erasergame 夢幻のように
Now, eins zwei drei! Connecting. Now, eins zwei drei! Shaking off death. Challenging the miracle to defy the game of destruction, Erasergame, like a dream.
神の与えし機械 Program さあ eins zwei drei! 重なり合う さあ eins zwei drei! 死を避けて
The mechanical program bestowed by the gods. Now, eins zwei drei! Overlapping. Now, eins zwei drei! Avoiding death.
怜悧なる傍観者 焦がれる生死よりも遠く 最果てにある箱庭で終わりのない奇跡があると信じていた
A shrewd bystander, far beyond the yearning life and death, believing that in the miniature garden at the farthest end, there is an endless miracle.
交わる 線と線 着飾る 大好きなアレコレソレ
Intersecting lines and lines, dressing up with all my favorite things.
そう いつだって 譲れないアイデンティティ
That's right, an identity I can never compromise, always.
手探り 手繰り寄せても 繰返し 絡まるの 気持ちの糸
Even if I grope and pull them close, over and over, the threads of emotion entangle.
ねぇ いつだって 諦めたままのディスタンス
Hey, the distance always left abandoned.
キリのない 振り出しでも 繋いでたいなら 外さない 秘め事
Even from an endless starting point, if I want to stay connected, I won't let go of this secret.
惹かれ 逢って 存在 綴る セカイ 共鳴させたなら
Attracted and meeting, if we made this world that spells our existence resonate,
ねぇ このままで ままで いられるかな 淡い期待に通せんぼ 塞いで曖昧 知らん顔 こうやって繋いでいられたなら
Hey, can we stay just like this? Blocked by faint expectations, plugging ears with vague ignorance. If we could stay connected like this,
痛い痛いのとちだ
It hurts, it hurts...
やめよよ やめよよ 傷つくのはもういやだ
Stop it, stop it, I don't want to get hurt anymore.
大丈夫 大丈夫 きっとすべてうまくいくよ
It's alright, it's alright, everything will surely work out fine.
やめよよ やめよよ 傷つくのはもういやだ
Stop it, stop it, I don't want to get hurt anymore.
ああ 意味もなく囁く
Ah, whispering for no reason.
この心揺さぶる ボール
The ball that shakes this heart.
私の心の中で 天使と悪魔が言う どちらに付くかはあなた次第だ
Inside my heart, an angel and a devil whisper; which side you take is entirely up to you.
狂いえないように 生粋迷いなさい
So that you won't go mad, get thoroughly lost.
目を閉じて 両耳塞いだ
I closed my eyes and plugged both ears.
私の心の中で 天使と悪魔が言う どちらの正体も自分自身だ
Inside my heart, an angel and a devil say—both of their true identities are yourself.
天国も地獄も 木の向くまま進め その場所で自分らしくいられるかどうか
Whether heaven or hell, keep moving as your heart desires. Can you truly be yourself in that place?
自分らしく笑えるかどうか
Can you smile as your true self?
のびた人陰を 歩道にならべ
Lining up our elongated shadows on the pavement
夕闇のなかを 君と歩いている
Walking with you through the twilight,
手をつないで いつまでもずっと
Holding hands forever and ever,
そばにいれたなら 泣けちゃうくらい
So close to you it makes me want to cry,
風が冷たくなって 冬の匂いがした
The wind grew colder, and it smelled of winter.
そろそろこの街に 君と近付ける
Soon, the season to get closer to you in this town
季節がくる
will arrive.
今年、最初の雪の華を
This year's very first snow flower,
ふたり寄り添って 眺めているこの時間に
As we snuggle up and gaze at it together,
幸せがあふれだす
happiness overflows.
甘えとか弱さじゃない ただ、キミを愛してる
It's not weakness or dependency, I just love you.
心からそう思った
I thought that from the bottom of my heart.
キミがいると どんなことでも
With you here, no matter what happens,
乗り切れるような 気持ちになってる
I feel like I can get through anything.
こんな日々が いつまでもきっと
Surely, days like these will continue
続いてくことを 祈っているよ
forever and ever, I pray.
風が窓を揺らし 夜は揺り起こして
The wind shakes the window, waking the night,
どんな悲しいことも ボクが笑顔へと変えてあげる
Any sadness, I will turn into a smile for you.
舞い落ちてきた雪の華が
The snow flowers falling around us
窓の外ずっと 降りやむことを知らずに
outside the window, without stopping,
ボクラの街を染める
paint our town.
誰かのために何かをしたいと思えるのが
Knowing that wanting to do something for someone
愛ということを知った
is what love truly means.
もしキミを失ったとしたなら
If I were to lose you,
星になってキミを照らすだろう
I'd become a star to shine on you.
笑顔も涙に濡れてる夜も いつもいつでもそばにいるよ
Even on nights soaked in tears, I'll always be by your side.
今年、最初の雪の華を ふたり寄り添って
This year's very first snow flower, snuggled up together,
眺めているこの時間に 幸せがあふれだす
As we gaze at it, happiness overflows.
甘えとか弱さじゃない ただ、キミとずっと このままで一緒にいたい
It's not weakness or dependency, I just want to stay like this with you forever.
素直にそう思える この街に降り積もってく 真っ白な雪の華
I honestly feel that way. Pure white snow flowers piling up on this town,
ふたりの胸にそっと 想い出を描くよ これからもキミと
Gently sketching memories in our hearts, from now on with you...
And that was "Yuki no Hana". Did you guys like the ballad
and the gondola riding all the way here?
It was a pretty flower, uh, flower snowflake, yes, that I rode on all the way here.
And did you guys like the guest part? Yeah!
I sang a lot of songs with the guests and a full-on medley that I put a lot of thought into.
I really want to talk more about the medley and the concept, but I think I won't have enough time for that.
Maybe I'll talk about that in a future stream. So...
And also thank you so much for my lovely guests for singing with me.
And also, thank you so much to my lovely guests for singing with me.
But there's still one more guest song! Yeah! And that's not the last song by the way, so...
no worries. There's going to be one more guest song that you guys are absolutely gonna love!
And, um, also, also, there's going to be one super exciting announcement that I've been waiting... super waiting to, uh, show you guys.
And, um, also, there's going to be one super exciting announcement that I've been waiting... super waiting to, uh, show you guys.
So please do look forward to that as well.
それと、えっと、雪の花とゲストパートどうでしたか? えー、あの、メドレーとかね、すごく、とても、あの、もう色々考えた上で企画したんで、
And um, how were Yuki no Hana and the guest parts? Um, for the medley, I planned it very, very carefully,
もう本当にね、いろいろ、自分の考えたこともう全部言いたいんですけど、ちょっとそこまで時間ないので、えっと、とにかくね、みんな気に入っていただけるととても嬉しいです。
and I really want to say everything I thought about, but there's not enough time for that. Anyway, I'd be so happy if you all liked it.
そしてね、あの素敵な先輩方と一绪に歌えてとっても嬉しかったです。本当にありがとうございました、先輩方!
And I was so happy to sing together with such wonderful senpais. Thank you so much, senpais!
そして、えっと、まだね、えっとゲストパート、えっとゲスト曲、まだ一曲あるんで、これから歌いますんでね、みんな最後まで見てください。
And um, there's still one more guest song, so we're going to sing it now. Everyone, please watch until the end!
あとね、あの、そのすぐあとにね、あの、もう一つとても素敵で嬉しい、ずっと待ち遠しかった告知と、お披露目があるので、みんな最後まで見てくださいね!
And also, right after that, there's another very wonderful, happy announcement and reveal I've been waiting for, so everyone please watch until the end!
では次の曲行きます。Please listen to the next song!
Now, let's go to the next song. Please listen to the next song!
運命の女神様が目を閉じた
The goddess of fate closed her eyes,
「なんて可愛い赤ん坊なんだこと。
"What an adorable baby she is.
そうだわ!あの子に魔法をかけて遊びましょう」
That's it! Let's cast a spell on her and play."
くぼんだ両目 痩せぎすな身体
Sunken eyes and a gaunt body—
私を見れば誰もが言うのです
whenever anyone looks at me, they say,
「化け物!お前は同じ人間じゃないんだよ」と
"Monster! You're not even human like the rest of us."
悲しいなんて思わない だって
I don't think it's sad, because
思えばほら また涙があふれてくるわ
whenever I think about it, see, tears overflow once more.
もしもし願いが一つ叶うなら
If even a single wish could come true,
世界でたった一人だけの友達を
I'd want just one single friend in all the world.
生きることは素晴らしいこと
Living is a wonderful thing—
そんな風に私も思ってみたい
I want to feel that way about life, too.
「鼠はどうして嫌われるのでしょう?」
"Why are mice so hated?"
彼らは笑って「汚いからだろう」
They laugh and say, "Because they're dirty."
「それなら答えて、目の見えない僕のために
"Then answer me this, for my sightless eyes:
見てみぬふりに理不尽な差別
Turning a blind eye to unreasonable discrimination—
それって鼠とどっちが汚い?」
which of the two is dirtier than a rat?"
後退る彼らに続けて言うんだ
Continuing as they back away, I say,
「二度とするな!」
"Don't ever do that again!"
嬉しいのになぜでしょう かって
Even though I'm happy, why is it
涙がほら やっぱりあふれてくるの
that tears, see, still overflow from my eyes?
もしものなりたいものになれるなら
If I could become whatever I wished,
あなたのの前では普通の女の子に
I'd want to be a normal girl before you.
思うほどに胸が苦しい どうして私たちは私なのですか
Thinking of it hurts my chest so much. Why am I who I am?
ねずみはなんで嫌われるのでしょう
Why are rats so hated?
彼らは笑って「汚いからだろう」
They laugh and say, "Because they're filthy."
それなら答えて 目の見えない僕のために
If that's so, answer this, for my sightless self—
見て見ぬふりに理不尽な差別
Turning a blind eye to unreasonable discrimination,
それってねずみとどっちが汚い？
between that and a rat, which is filthier?
後退る彼らに続けて言うんだ「二度とするな！」
Stepping back, I tell them, "Never do that again!"
嬉しいのになぜでしょう
Why do I feel so happy?
だって 涙が ほら やっぱり あふれてくるのです
Because the tears, look, are overflowing after all.
もしもなりたいものになれるなら あなたの前では普通の女の子に
If I could become whatever I wished to be, in front of you, I'd be a normal girl.
思うほどに胸が苦しい
The more I think about it, the more my chest aches.
どうして私は私なのでしょう
Why must I be who I am?
君は優しい女の子なのに いつも自分を責める
You're such a gentle girl, yet you always blame yourself.
慰めてあげたい君を そうだ ここに咲いた
I want to comfort you. That's right, I'll give you
花を君にあげよう それは見事な白いユリの花
a flower that bloomed right here—a magnificent white lily.
そっと君の近くに置いていくよ
I'll gently leave it right by your side.
運命の女神様は意地悪だ 「見すぼらしいあの子を見たらどんなことするんだろう、見ものね」
The goddess of fate is so mean: "Let's see what happens when she sees that shabby child, shall we?"
目よ治れと魔法をかける 花は黒く闇のように染まる
Casting a spell for your eyes to heal, the flower is dyed black like darkness.
それは不吉な黒いユリの花 「お前には彼からの贈り物だ、さあヒロイン、お出ましだ」
It's an ominous black lily flower: "A gift from him to you, now behold the heroine."
あぁ 前に彼から 贈りものだ 空の上の
Ah, a gift from him before, from high above the sky...
あぁ これはきっと罰です だって 私神の許しなくずずに恋をし
Ah, this is surely my punishment, because I dared to fall in love without God's forgiveness.
だから いっそ死んでしまえばいいのでしょうか あなたは叫ぶ
Would it be better if I just died right now? You shout:
「泣かないで 僕がずっと死ぬまでそばにいる。だから、今日から君は普通の女の子さ」
"Don't cry. I will always stay by your side until I die. So starting today, you're a normal girl."
…それにみなよ？ 悪夢ような魔法はほら 解けたみたい
...Look up at the sky, won't you? It seems the nightmare-like spell has finally melted away.
And that was “Tsumi no Namae” with my promised ladies.
And that was "Tsumi no Namae" with my promised ladies.
Did you guys like it?
Let's just say that was the last song, or I said that was the last song even though I did not say that a few minutes ago.
I think this live is already over. What should I do? What should I do?
You guys want more?
Shut up!
Or more like, I still have this exciting announcement to make. Can you guys guess what it is?
Yeah.
It is a new original song! Yeah, it is a new song called “Twilight,” written by Yunuske-san with lyrics written by Yuuniku-san.
It is a new original song! Yeah, it is a new song called "Twilight," written by Yunuske-san with lyrics written by Yuuniku-san.
It is a really, really, really cool song.
And with a really really cool MV,
that will be shown right after this live!
Yeah!
So when you finish watching this, please,
go directly straight to the MV 'cause you will regret it if you don't.
go directly straight to the MV 'cause you'll regret it if you don't.
It is a song that is based on this angel devil theme,
It is a song that is based on this angel-devil theme
that this live is also based on, or more like I based the live theme to the song.
that this live is also based on... or more like I based the live theme on the song.
So if you put them two together, it becomes a work of art!
So if you put them together, it becomes a work of art!
Yes! But before you go to the MV after this, I will be performing...
Yes! One last song for you guys, which is obviously, obviously Twilight! I will be releasing...
Yes! One last song for you guys, which is obviously, obviously Twilight! I will be releasing—
I will be performing the song for you guys right after this, so I hope you guys enjoy that as my last song for today.
performing the song for you guys right after this, so I hope you guys enjoy that as my last song for today.
I will be saying this in Japanese now.
ええと、では、ええとね、
Um, well, um...
なんと、新曲出します！Twilightという曲になっています。
And now, I'm releasing a new song! It's called "Twilight".
ええと、由乃一さんに書いていただき、ええと歌詞は、ええと牛肉さんに書いていただきました。
Um, Yunosuke-san wrote the music, and Gyuniku-san wrote the lyrics.
とってもね、かっこいい曲になっています。
It's a really cool song. And what's more,
そしてなんとね、このライブのすぐ後に、そのめちゃくちゃいいMVを、あの、出していただけますんで、みんなこのライブのすぐ後にそっちに飛んでいただけるととっても嬉しいです。
right after this live, that amazing MV will be released, so I'd be so happy if you all flew over there right after this live!
その、あの曲、新曲Twilightは、ええと天使と悪魔のこちらのライブのテーマに合わせた曲になっています。
The new song "Twilight" is tailored to the theme of this angel and devil live.
でね、ええと最後もう1曲お披露目したいかと思うんですけど、なんと、その新しい曲Twilightを披露させていただきます。
And well, I'd like to premiere one last song, and I will be performing the new song "Twilight".
ではね、あの最後の曲Twilight、聞いてください、Please listen to my last song for today, and thank you so much for watching until the end, please listen to Twilight!
So please listen to the final song, "Twilight". Please listen to my last song for today, and thank you so much for watching until the end, please listen to "Twilight"!
じゃあさ 私は今
So here's where we stand,
私である事実も
Am I who I am?
定められない定まらない
I can't decide, it wavers
存在なんだと、that's fine with me
That's who I am, that's fine with me
平行線保つだけじゃ意味なく
Maintaining status quo has no meaning,
heads or tails, それだけではなく
Heads or tails, that's not all
fallen angel, ascended devil
禍々しい姿
Manifesting my twisted form
求められている矛盾する自由も
Demanded of me, contradictory freedom too
ひとつの意志
As a single will
求められている自分をただ
The self I demand to be recognized
認めたい
I just want to accept
Twilight 熱く広がる
Twilight spreads far and wide,
刹那の黄昏よ
A fleeting moment of dusk
try out, 掛け違えても
Try out, even if it goes wrong
全ての指標だから
It's all an indicator
深層のback to back
The depths go back-to-back,
奈落から高くまで暗黒の声で
From hell to way up high in a dark voice
羽ばたいた
Taking flight
大体の全体が間違いで生まれる
Most of everything was born of a mistake
存在じゃないのか関係性
Or is that relationship already null?
既に無味も同然 high and low
High and low, negligible conclusion
無視の結論 fallen angel, ascended devil
Fallen angel, ascended devil
歪な形を求めている
Seeking a distorted shape
浸す布を捩るように
Like wringing out a soaked cloth
宇宙以上地球未完の
More than universe, uncompleted earth
定義なんて主張だけです
Definitions are just assertions
白と黒が大切なのは分かるけれど
I get that black and white are important, but
私は私はどこ、私は誰
Where am I, who am I, what am I?
私は何者か
What kind of entity am I?
私は今、私は今
Now, right now,
私へと混ざり合うの
Blending into myself
背反的な翼で高くへ飛び立てば
Taking flight on contradictory wings
曖昧なのも小さくまとめて映るから
Making even ambiguities smaller and clear
twilight, 両手に乗せた
Twilight, held in both hands,
紬い交ぜを説く
Explaining the intertwined web
try out, 掛け違えても
Try out, even if it goes wrong,
訂正はいらない
It doesn't need correction
be oneself, be myself
revisit, ふたつで
Revisit, two sides
be oneself, be myself ひとつな
Be oneself, be myself, as one
be oneself, be myself
revisit, 心の指標だから
Revisit, indicators of the heart
Thank you so much for all of your support since my debut over 3 years ago!
Your love & cheers are what made this live possible
Your love and cheers are what made this live possible,
& I will do my best to continue being your ~ANGEL & DEVIL~
and I will do my best to continue being your ~ANGEL & DEVIL~
見に来てくれて
Thank you for coming
ありがとう♥
to see me!